# Anthony Fu

Software Engineer

hi@antfu.me

in



(i) (9)

# About

My name is Anthony Fu, a master of computer science student and a freelance software engineer. My passion for software lies with dreaming up ideas and making them come true with elegant interfaces. I take great care in the experience, architecture, and code quality of the things I build.

I am also an open-source enthusiast and maintainer. I love how collaboration and knowledge sharing happens through open-source and I am happy to see what I do could eventually feedback to the community and industry.

# **Projects**

#### Vitest 0 7

A blazing fast unit test framework powered by Vite.

**★** 5701

#### Slidev 0 7

Presentation Slides for Developers.

**★** 21951

#### UnoCSS O 7

Instant on-demand atomic CSS engine.

**★** 6058

#### VueUse 7

Collection of essential Vue Composition API utils.

**★** 11048

### Nuxt 0 7

The Hybrid Vue(3) Framework.

★ 8279

#### Vite () 7

Next generation frontend tooling.

**45538** 

More Projects...

## Work Experience

#### NuxtLabs Software Engineer

Sep 2021 - Present | Remote

- Integrated Vite into Nuxt 3 resulted in 50x faster development time.
- Authored `unplugin` unifing the API between Webpack and Vite.
- Created Vitest that improved the developer experience on testing.

#### Open Source OSS Developer

Jan 2015 - Present | Github

- Vue.js & Vite.js Core Team Member
- Received 15,000+ stars on personal projects
- · Maintaining numerous popular projects

## ByteDance Ltd. Front-end Development Intern

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020 | Shanghai, China

#### In Product R & D and Engineering Architecture Department

 Developed a marketplace for low-code/no-code platforms with integrated documentation site, demo and coding playground.

#### Foremost Groups, Inc. Technical Consultant

Oct 2019 - Jun 2020 | Taipei, Taiwan (Remote)

Provided technical support on market data collecting and analyzing

## Fastfish Ltd. Software Engineer Intern

Jul 2016 - Sep 2016 | Hangzhou, China

## Worked on developing POS system in C#.NET and ASP.NET

• Improved back-end ASP.NET server performance by optimization SQL compounding algorithm

# Stacks

Frontend TypeScript, JavaScript, Vue, Nuxt, Vite

Backend Node, MongoDB, MySQL, Serverless, Nginx, Docker

Mobile Android, Kotlin, PWA

DevOps Firebase, AWS, Azure, AliCloud

Languages Python, Java, C/C++, C#, Go

## Education

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science, Tamkang University, New Taipei

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

## Talks

New Ways to Vue, Vue London 2021

Oct 20, 2021, Slides

How the new tools and techniques affect the way we view and build applications

Composable Vue, VueDay 2021

Apr 29, 2021, Slides

Talked about the reactivity system and Composition API in Vue.js

Develop with Vite, Vue Beijing 2021

Mar 29, 2021, Slides

Introduce to Vite, the next generation frontend tooling

Binjiang Front-End Developer Salon, Hangzhou, Bingjiang Front-End Union

Sep 26, 2020, Slides

Talked about the reactivity system and Composition API in Vue.js

# Awards

Idea Maker Competition Masterpiece Award, Oriental Institute of Technology

**Graduation Project Competition Masterpiece Award**, Tamkang University Jun 2018

First Class Scholarship for Academics (top one), Tamkang University

Nov 2016

# Languages

Chinese (Native speaker), English (Fluent), Japanese (Intermediate)

Online Version

Last updated at August 2nd 2022, 6:39:57 am